Roberto Rogelio Marto Ramirez

Mobile Developer

Las Tunas, Cuba | +53 53411868 | mailto:rrmarto89@gmail.com

Summary

Computer Sciences Engineer (Havana, UCI, 2013), experienced in mobile development with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Strong engineering professional skilled in Java, Android, Flutter, Web development, Agile Methodologies and Relational Databases.

Work experience

Flutter Developer

2019 - PRESENT

FREELANCE

- Analysis of user requirements and translation of customer needs into application design.
- Clean, modular, and robust code using state management.
- Created and published applications for Android and iOS using flutter.

Technologies used: Flutter, Kotlin, Java, Swift, REST, GraphQL, WebSockets, Git, GoogleMaps, Mapbox, Firebase, Twilio, Stripe.

Software Developer

2017 - 2019

GDAI

- FullStack Developer.
- Mobile developer.
- Implementation of web interfaces.
- Implementation of SOAP and REST web services.
- Modeling of database structures in Oracle and PostgreSQL.

Technologies used: Java, Android, Swift, Flutter, GraphQL, Apollo, SOAP, REST, HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Angular, Maven, Git, Rational Team Concert (RTC), Oracle, PostgresSQL, SCRUM.

Software Developer

2015 - 2017

CIDI

- Design and implementation of web interfaces.
- Android Development.
- Implementation and maintenance of source code in different layers of architecture.
- Design of procedures and functions in SQL Server.

Technologies used: Android, C#, HTML5, JQuery, CSS, SQL Server, Visual Studio, TFS.

Computer Science Specialist

2013 - 2014

University of Informatics Sciences

- Android Development.
- Design and implementation of web interfaces.
- Design and implementation of unit tests using JUnit.
- Advanced Administration of GNU / Linux Systems.

Technologies used: *Java EE, Android, Spring, JUnit, HTML5,* CSS3, JQuery, Maven, Git, PostgresSQL, SCRUM, XP.



Technologies

Programming Languages: Java, Kotlin, Dart, Swift, C#.

Web: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript,

Angular.

Frameworks: Spring MVC, Spring

Boot, Bootstrap, JQuery.

WS: SOAP, REST, GraphQL, Websockets.

DB: PostgreSQL, MySql, Oracle, MongoDB.

CVS: Git, SVN, RTC, TFS.

IDE: Eclipse, Netbeans, IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio Code, Android Studio, XCode.

Testing: JUnit.

Methodologies: Scrum, XP, RUP.

Operating System: Windows, Linux,

MacOS.

Skills

- Algorithm design
- Analysis and design of solutions.
- High level of abstraction.
- Systems requirements engineering.
- Unitary and functional testing.
- Teamwork.
- Adaptability to changing environments.
- Work under pressure.

Language

Spanish

Native Speaker

English

Intermediate/Advance proficiency

Education

Computer Science Engineer

University of Informatics Science

2008 - 2013

Training

- Postgraduate course:
 Advanced Mobile
 Development, 2015, Havana Cuba.
- Postgraduate course:
 Advanced management in
 GNU/Linux, 2014, Havana,
 Cuba.
- Postgraduate course: Android Development,2013, Havana Cuba.